Dmitriy Vasilyuk

510 851 1078

⊘

vasilyuk.dm@gmail.com



github.com/reasonmethis



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

FULL-STACK BLOCKCHAIN AND AI DEVELOPER

Transitioned from theoretical particle physics to a 15-year career as a professional poker player, owing a high long-term winrate to a self-built suite of tools for strategy analysis. Engagement with DeFi and algorithmic trading led to positions as a full-stack blockchain developer. Recently created and sold an AI assistant app for chatting with a company's private data.

SKILLS

Tech: Python, Typescript, C++, Solidity, SQL, React, Langchain, Hardhat, Foundry, AWS, GCP, PyTorch, REST APIs, LLM agents

Fundamentals: theoretical physics, higher mathematics, game theory, statistics, machine learning, algorithms & data structures

Miscellaneous: poker, analytic philosophy, scientific skepticism, teaching, 5 languages, writing & editing, accessibility issues/tools

WORK EXPERIENCE

Al Assistant Developer – Redwood City, CA

Sep 2023 – Present

- Created Al assistant apps (1) DocDocGo Carbon, licensed to <u>Carbon, Inc.</u>, (2) DocDocGo Core, OSS, <u>featured</u> by Streamlit
- DDG Carbon: ChatGPT-like chat with company's Confluence docs via Google Chat connected to Flask API & vector DB
- DDG Core: "infinite" research loop ingest 100s of sites on user's topic into knowledge base, use it for chat and reports

Blockchain Developer at Peaze - Redwood City, CA

Aug 2023 – Nov 2023

- Developed smart contracts to enable gasless cross-chain transactions using EIP 712/2612 to encode/sign meta-txs
- Redesigned and wrote portions of Next.js API for relaying such transactions; crafted user-facing documentation

Blockchain Developer at Standard Creative - Redwood City, CA

Dec 2022 – Jul 2023

- Wrote smart contracts along with extensive test suite, performed audits & gas optimizations, created documentation
- Implemented parts of frontend, integrated frontend with contracts and IPFS, created automated e2e frontend tests

DeFi and Algo Trader - Emeryville, CA

Aug 2021 – Dec 2022

- Built perpetual futures trading bot on Solana blockchain; traded manually and algorithmically across DeFi protocols
- Built Telegram bot with backend leveraging Python data science stack for time-series analysis, portfolio optimization

Professional Poker Player – Emeryville, CA

May 2007 – Oct 2021

- Beat mid & high stakes limit hold'em games with win-rate 1.9BB/100 over last 1M hands on PokerStars and other sites
- Succeeded by building applications (Python/C++ see below) to help play, analyze strategies, alert to weaknesses

Co-founder at Q-Wager – El Cerrito, CA

Jun 2006 – Aug 2009

Made C++ app to beat online casinos by optimally auto-playing blackjack and collecting bonuses, 300+ paying customers

PROJECTS

Crypto Trader {Python} – trading bots for EVM-compatible blockchains and Solana

- Solana bot (a) runs market-making strategy for perp futures; (b) places +EV taker orders based on orderbook and oracle
- EVM bot queries liquidity pool smart contracts and executes on-chain swaps based on predefined triggers, sends alerts

Crypto Analyzer {Python} – Telegram bot offering tools for analyzing and monitoring crypto price data

- Fetches live & historical prices, calculates autocorrelation, volatility, trends, impermanent loss, makes graphical reports
- Each user can set one's own parameters and create alerts to monitor crypto positions; public vs advanced features

Poker Analyzer {Python} – game analysis suite: advanced filters & stats, detects players' weaknesses during game

- During play parses game history, adds to custom-made database, updates all stats, reports deviations from reference
- Rich query language to filter player game data and 89GB of Nash equilibrium strategy, generates reports & quizzes
- Monte-Carlo sims of equilibrium & non-equilibrium play to calculate EVs and find exploitative strategy adjustments

VocabMeThis {Python} – mobile-first web app to test user's vocabulary and teach new words at auto-adjusting difficulty level

- 125000 words & definitions, with algorithm to rank by difficulty by constructing frequency dictionary from NLTK corpora
- Data cleaning algorithms to identify different forms of the same word, replace one-word definitions with proper ones

Game Manager {C++} – application to play professional online poker with no mouse or keyboard on multiple tables

- Analyzes mic sound, classifies it (S vs SH vs AH etc.), translates into required action on poker table, adapts to noise
- Monitors poker tables for special events (opponent came, good seat freed up, etc.), alerts and performs needed action

ReasonMeThis {HTML, CSS, JavaScript} – philosophy and physics blog at www.reasonmethis.com

- Over 30 articles on philosophy of language, anthropic reasoning, multiverse, entropy, consciousness, and other topics
- Interactive JavaScript animations of physics and math concepts e.g. desynchronizing double pendula to illustrate chaos

EDUCATION

Master of Arts in Physics – UC Berkeley

- Received Outstanding Graduate Student Instructor award for excellence in teaching
- Conducted research in string theory as part of Ph.D. program, switched careers before completing Ph.D.

Bachelor of Arts in Physics – *UC Berkeley*

■ Earned **2**nd **place** in <u>BAUPC</u>, Harvard-run physics competition